Last year, everyone shipped AI into production.
This year, everyone is discovering the same ugly thing.
AI quality doesn't fail loudly — it drifts.
A retrieval index goes quietly stale.
A model update changes behavior.
And nobody notices until customers do — days later.
Your dashboards logged all of it and told you nothing, because every single response still looked fine.
We built DRIFT: the early-warning court for AI quality.
DRIFT watches your AI's answers in production and scores every one — quality, hedging, truncation, retrieval hits, latency.
What you're seeing is a healthy support bot.
Boring on purpose.
But here's what makes DRIFT different from every observability tool: DRIFT never trusts its own suspicion.
Before anything alerts a human, the suspicion goes on trial.
Degradation has started — planted retrieval decay.
Notice: every individual response still passes any reasonable threshold.
This is the failure mode that kills every threshold-based monitor.
So DRIFT holds a hearing.
A prosecutor argues the decline is real — armed with regression the code computed, never the model.
A defense attacks with every innocent explanation: did traffic shift toward harder questions?
One outlier user?
Time of day?
Scorer noise?
Too few samples?
And a judge rules on a fixed standard of proof.
Our C.I.
proves this works.
Three fixture streams run on every commit: the court must convict planted drift, must acquit pure noise — and must acquit the hard case: a traffic-mix shift where the aggregate trend is genuinely negative, but nothing is actually broken.
That acquittal is a machine-checked claim, public in our Actions tab.
Every alert-fatigue horror story you've heard is that third case, unhandled.
The trend just survived cross-examination.
Now — and this is the product — DRIFT doesn't hand you a red dot.
It hands you a countdown.
Quality crosses your floor in three to five hours at the current rate.
Probable cause: retrieval decay.
Hours of warning, a cause to investigate, and a confidence range.
Pure deterministic math — a language model never produces a number this system acts on.
And when the fit is too weak to trust, DRIFT refuses to guess.
A range is honest.
A confident number from a bad fit is theater.
Every forecaster demos well once.
So DRIFT grades itself in public.
Here's the predicted crossing window laid over what actually happened — the real crossing landed inside the predicted window.
The alert's outcome is backfilled into the ledger, and the dashboard shows live alert precision.
No monitoring vendor shows you their false-alarm rate.
We made it the headline metric.
Who pays for this?
Anyone whose AI talks to customers.
A support bot doing ten thousand conversations a day that quietly degrades for three days is thirty thousand bad customer experiences — refunds, escalations to human agents at dollars per ticket, and churn you can't attribute.
DRIFT turns that into a two-hour incident with a named cause.
LangSmith, Arize, Braintrust — excellent tools that tell you what your quality was.
None of them forecast, and none of them cross-examine their own alarms.
DRIFT ships both, and self-reports its precision — a metric no incumbent publishes.
And this is why AMD matters — not as a sponsor logo, but as the economics.
Scoring every response, plus two extra reasoning passes per suspicion, is exactly the workload per-token API pricing punishes.
On one MI300X, 192 gigabytes of memory holds our sensing model and the judge simultaneously, at flat cost.
Adversarial verification is the feature incumbents can't afford to build on API economics.
Our moat is partly a hardware-cost artifact — and we say so.
Everything you saw is live: real models, one-command onboarding onto any OpenAI-compatible endpoint — including a vLLM box on AMD Developer Cloud — and a C.I.
tab that machine-checks the court's judgment on every commit.
AI quality doesn't fail loudly.
Now it doesn't have to fail silently either.
DRIFT — verdict first, alert second.